ANGUS INNES

MOBILE: 07990 800 961 EMAIL: A.INNES9@GMAIL.COM

4+ years' experience leading cross-functional teams and managing products from concept, to launch, to thousands of users. I am experienced in web app development, project management and telecommunications. I'm looking to join a company that values innovation, making a social impact and operational excellence.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Nov 2018 – Present

Jangala, Strategy & Product Manager

LONDON, UK

Jangala, a startup charity providing internet access in international humanitarian emergencies. We make Wi-Fi routers that dramatically reduce the technical barriers to installing and maintaining Wi-Fi. Since joining as the first hire, Jangala has grown exponentially becoming social impact partner to Lenovo and Arm, and raised over £500,000 in funding to provide internet access to schools and aid workers as well as industrial applications across three continents.

- Responsible for delivering new products from the ground up including our response to the pandemic, Get Box a post-able WiFi router running custom software to enable low-income communities across the UK to access digital services, taking a hardware product from idea to prototype in under 2 months.
- Worked with user research to inform requirements documents and map user flows for creation of instructions, onboarding and website design, for users and purchasers.
- Strategic lead and planner, guiding workshops with founders on product discovery, organizational vision and execution strategy to scope and order product roadmaps with metric led objectives and key results.
- Scrum master for development, delivering new features and functionality. Responsible for testing and launch of prototypes, running user testing program with 50 of our at-home connectivity device during lockdowns, to inform customer focus and capture valuable bugs and feedback for feature prioritisation.
- Methodical and versed in agile ways of working, managed the backlog to drive feature prioritisation, sprint sizing and holding frequent retrospectives to capture learnings for continuous process improvement.
- Technically adept, using programming skills to create key tools for scalability an IoT software update system for remote devices in the field and a data pipeline for logging product usage.
- Data-literate, responsible for the specification and design of the Jangala database for core partner metrics and using modern web technologies to automate query execution and impact report generation.
- Analytical, leading creation of business plan with the Managing Director, pricing and financial modelling, competitor and sales analysis to scope our investment case and report social impact to funding partners.
- Key member of the team, pitching and securing £250,000 in funding from Lenovo, the biggest pitch win and forming a long-term partnership worth over 5 times the total previous capital raised.
- A strong communicator, I am used to delivering reports and managing stakeholders across the business and time zones, including founders, board directors, clients, partners, non-technical funders and engineers.
- Responsible for writing our monthly newsletter program for 500-person audience.

Sep 2016 – Oct 2018

Deloitte Digital, Technology Consultant

LONDON, UK

Trained as a software engineer and business analyst on the graduate scheme, spending two years at the Home Office, completing an enterprise scale digital transformation.

- Agile lead for DevOps team in cloud migration to AWS for a multi-million user UK Home Office application
- Software lead for the implementation of data logging and monitoring subsequently used to reveal inconsistencies and pain points in user journeys, inform the product roadmap and technical debt backlog
- Day to day manager of live services for Home Office web application, communicating with non-technical product owners and ensuring SLA agreements were met
- Managed two junior members of the DevOps team, onboarded to increase capacity during the migration
- Led a knowledge sharing initiative that trained 90 engineering managers in its first year
- Took initiative to gain qualifications in AWS Solutions Architecture

Apr 2016 – July 2016

AKQA London, Product Intern

LONDON, UK

AKQA is a design and innovation company. As part of the Future Academy innovation lab I worked in a cross-functional team, applying design thinking to solve creative briefs.

- Managed sprints and teams through ideation, user research and UX design to deliver creative work for Tag Heuer, Jamie Oliver and Google.
- Pitched work to C-Level clients and presented new ventures to 400 colleagues in London.

Mar 2015

The Selco Foundation, Economist Intern

BANGALORE, INDIA

• Economist intern at a solar energy company in Bangalore to understand microfinance and renewables. Contributed to an investment framework for the World Wildlife Fund.

Oct 2014 Saatchiinvest VC/The Bakery, Business Analysis Intern LONDON, UK

• Assisted chief investor for The Bakery/Saatchiinvest Venture Capital, running client workshops and learning about London's start-up and early-stage investment ecosystem.

EDUCATION		
2016	British Computing Society, International Diploma in Solution Development	LONDON, UK
2016	British Computing Society, International Diploma in Business Analysis	LONDON, UK
2015-2016	General Assembly, Web Development Immersive Portfolio available at http://beruti.github.io	LONDON, UK
2011-2014	Newcastle University: Economics and Business Management, BA Hons Firsts in Behavioural Economics and Advertising.	NEWCASTLE, UK

OTHER INTERESTS

- Public Speaking: Frequent speaker as a member of the City of London Toastmasters, delivering speeches on storytelling and leadership.
- Start-ups: Won StartUp Weekend in 2018 with an e-commerce product using data analytics to audit and verify supply chain ethics.
- Charity: Chef and host for three supper clubs to fundraise £2000 for The Lada Rally 2018 a race across
 Europe supporting refugee charities.
- Running: Ran the New Forest trail Marathon 2017 to raise money for mental health charity Sane